802-299-9460

PROFILE

UX designer with over five years of experience at a quickly growing Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) company. Proven ability to translate business objectives into technical solutions. Trusted liaison between technical and non-technical teams. Consistently receives high customer satisfaction ratings and top performance reviews.

PROFESSIONAL TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE

STARTUP INSTITUTE

Competitive eight-week intensive program that helps individuals develop the skills, mindset and network to be high-impact at a high-growth company.

Web Design Student

June 2016 – Present

- Coursework includes HTML, CSS, user-centered design, rapid ideation, navigation and flow, and wire-framing.
- Designed and conducted user experience research for partner company.

POWERSCHOOL GROUP, LLC

Leading K-12 Student Information System (SIS) in the nation; acquired InfoSnap in November 2015.

Consultant and Project Manager

December 2015 - May 2016

- Analyzed implementation project processes and adjusted to increase efficiencies.
- Developed initial specifications for new products and features based on stakeholders' business objectives.
- Managed internal rollout of new products including coordinating communications, developing and executing trainings, and writing technical documentation.

INFOSNAP

Leading provider of cloud-based enrollment and registration management solutions for schools nationwide.

Team Leader (Specialized Services Group)

December 2013 – December 2015

Managed a team of Senior Solution Specialists working with the largest, most strategically important customers. Responsible for timeliness of projects, quality of configurations and success of implementations.

- Developed approach for managing enterprise customer implementation projects.
- Discovered and defined custom product development needs and coordinated interdepartmentally to develop, test and implement solutions. Brought completed product enhancements to customers for rollout and fine-tuning.
- Identified and proactively addressed project risk points, often by incorporating and managing resources outside of the team.
- Led technical configuration for first customer on a new system platform including working with the development team to QA features, troubleshoot bugs, and specify new features and design updates.

Team Leader

December 2012 – December 2013

Managed a team of Online Solution Specialists and was responsible for their project success and professional development.

- Designed user workflow for and performed usability testing on first lottery management implementation.
- Developed and organized InfoSnap University (a three-day internal workshop series).

ALISON FANNING PAGE 2

Senior Solution Specialist

June 2012 - December 2012

Managed projects for the most strategically important and challenging customers.

- Became trusted subject matter expert and developed best practices for integration with PowerSchool.
- Mentored and trained new team members.
- Helped re-engineer the implementation project to align with the needs of the public school market.

Online Solution Specialist

November 2010 – June 2012

Responsible for over twenty customers, running simultaneous registration implementation projects.

- Designed and built customized forms and administrative toolsets based on customers' business goals.
- Consulted with and trained customers on best use of tools and features.
- Created public school specific best practices and internal training program.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

VILLA ESPERANZA

Volunteer Website Manager

August 2010 – November 2013

Non-profit providing scholarship and mentoring programs for first generation college students. Updated WordPress-hosted website and served on the scholarship committee.

SUSTAINABILITY LEADERS NETWORK

Program Assistant

September 2010 – September 2013

Non-profit supporting social and environmental change leaders using a systems thinking approach toward sustainability. Managed website including editing new website before it went live and performing ongoing maintenance and updates.

KIVA

Volunteer Translator

October 2009 – May 2011

Non-profit providing micro-loans to borrowers. Translated from Spanish to English for lenders.

SUSTAINABILITY INSTITUTE

Donella Meadows Fellows Program Assistant

June 2009 – February 2010

Climate Interactive Program Coordinator

October 2009 – February 2010

Non-profit focused on sustainability thinking and training. Coordinated housing, catering, travel and logistics.

EDUCATION

BATES COLLEGE, Lewiston, ME

Bachelor's Degree, Latin American Studies (self-designed major), Spanish (minor)

Semester abroad in Ecuador